Guide to the World Student Christian Federation Board of Trustees in the U.S. Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
World Student Christian Federation Board of Trustees in the U.S. Records
1949-1988
RG 46B
Yale University Divinity School Library
8.5
(10 boxes)
The material in this collection consists of administrative and financial records of the WSCF U.S. Board of Trustees. The World Student Christian Federation was created in 1895 as an international student Christian movement which could encourage and coordinate the work of national student Christian movements.The WSCF had headquarters in Geneva, but maintained a U.S. Board of Trustees to guide policy and financial operations in North America.
World's Student Christian Federation
World Student Christian Federation
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Newton Thurber
Biographical / Historical
The World's Student Christian Federation was created in 1895 to fulfill its founders' vision of an international student Christian movement which could encourage and coordinate the work of existing national student Christian movements, as well as stimulate the formation of unified student movements in countries where they did not exist. The U. S. Board of Trustees was entrusted with financial jurisdiction over the U.S. operations of the WSCF.
Scope and Contents
The first series of this collection contains correspondence and minutes of the Board of Trustees of the World Student Christian Federation, which for many years had its headquarters at 475 Riverside Drive, New York. Margaret Flory was chairperson of the Board of Trustees during the period covered by these records. Other correspondents are William S. Ellis, John E. Jordan, Ruth Harris. Much of the work of the Board of Trustees related to financial oversight and appeals, but the correspondence also contains material related to student Christian movement activities in Africa, Asia, and Latin America, and efforts to resuscitate the North American student Christian movement in the 1980s.
These records are complemented by the Archives of the WSCF and WSCF North America Regional Office held at YDSL, as well as the personal papers of Ruth Harris and Margaret Flory.
Arrangement
I. Administrative Files
II. Financial Records
III. Tax Reports
Ecumenical movement; Universities and colleges -- Religion; World Student Christian Federation; World's Student Christian Federation
- Administrative Files, 1949-1989; Series I
  - Correspondence regarding financial matters; Certificate of Incorporation, 1964-1968 (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - Correspondence; minutes of Board of Trustees meetings (1969 Jun, 1970 May), 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - Correspondence; minutes of Board of Trustees meetings (1971 Nov, 1972 Oct, 1973 Sep, 1973 Oct); minutes of Executive Committee (1973 Oct)' "Committee on Friends" (1974 Apr); Development Task Force (1974 Apr), 1971-1974 (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - Correspondence; minutes of special meeting of the Board of Trustees (1975 May) (Box 6, Folder 138)
  - Correspondence; minutes of Board of Trustees meeting (1976 Mar) (Box 6, Folder 139)
  - Correspondence, memos, collected material re. SCM movements; minutes of Board of Trustees meeting (1977 Mar), by-laws (Box 6, Folder 140-141)
  - Correspondence, memos; minutes of Board of Trustees meeting (1978 Jun) (Box 6, Folder 142)
  - Correspondence, memos; minutes of Board of Trustees meeting (1979 Oct) (Box 6, Folder 143)
  - Correspondence, memos; minutes of WSCF/ US Church Relations Committee, and of Board of Trustees meeting (1980 Dec) (Box 6, Folder 144-145)
  - Correspondence, collected material incl. regarding National Ecumenical Student Conference at University of California Berkeley August 1981; minutes of Board of Trustees meeting (1981 Jun) (Box 6, Folder 146-147)
  - Correspondence, memos, incl. Committee on Church Relations; minutes of Board of Trustees meeting (1982 Sep) (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - Collected material re. WSCF and SCMs, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 149)
  - Correspondence, documents re. reviving of student Christian movement in the U.S.; minutes of Board of Trustees (1983 Jun) (Box 6, Folder 150-151)
  - Correspondence, grant and financial reports, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 152-153)
  - Collected material: WSCF reports, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - Correspondence; minutes of Board of Trustees meeting (1985 Apr) (Box 7, Folder 155-156)
  - Collected material re. WSCF, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 157)
  - Correspondence, financial documents; minutes of Board of Trustees meeting (1986 Oct) (Box 7, Folder 158)
  - Correspondence, documentation regarding new directions for Ecumenical Student Christian Ministry in the U.S., financial appeals and responses; minutes of Board of Trustees meeting (1987 Mar, May, Sep, Nov) (Box 7, Folder 159-160)
  - Correspondence, financial appeals; minutes of Board of Trustees meeting (1988 May) (Box 7, Folder 161-162)
  - Correspondence, financial documentation; flyer re. women in the WSCF, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 163)
  - Letterhead, documents to be used as templates (Box 7, Folder 164)
- Financial Records, 1949-1988; Series II
  - Financial Statements: WSCF / United Student Christian Council, 1949-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Financial Ledgers, 1963-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Financial transactions, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Financial transactions, 1969 Jan-Dec (Box 1, Folder 7-18)
  - Bank correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Income received, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Philippe Maury Fund / new WSCF headquarters, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
  - Seaman Estate, 1963-70 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Financial transactions, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 24-35)
  - Philippe Maury Fund, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Income Desposits, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Financial transactions, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 41-47)
  - Income received, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 48-52)
  - Financial transactions, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 53-55)
  - Financial transactions, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 55-58)
  - Financial transactions, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 59-60)
  - Financial transactions, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 61-66)
  - Financial transactions, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 67-71)
  - Re. emergency medical expenses of WSCF Honorary Treasurer M.E. Prabhaker, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Financial transactions, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 73-76)
  - Financial transactions, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 77-80)
  - Financials transactions, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 81-84)
  - Financial transactions, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 85-89)
  - Financial transactions, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 90-93)
  - Financial transactions, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 94-98)
  - Financial transactions, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 99-101)
  - Financial transactions, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 102-104)
  - Financial transactions, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 105-108)
  - Financial transactions, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 109-112)
  - Financial transactions, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 113-116)
- Tax Reports, 1958-; Series III
  - Tax reports and correspondence, 1958-1969 (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Tax reports, 1970-1973 (Box 5, Folder 118-120)
  - Tax Reports, 1975-1988 (Box 5, Folder 121-134)
- Addendum: Newton Thurber Files, Series IV
  - Trustees correspondence, 1969-1997 (Box 8, Folder 164a)
  - Trustee meeting minutes, 1965-1990 (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Trustee meeting minutes, 1990-1993 (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - Trustee meeting minutes, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 167)
  - WSCF Senior Friends, 1993-1995 (Box 8, Folder 168-169)
  - Centennial: Archiving project, 1993-1995 (Box 8, Folder 170-172)
  - Centennial: Events, 1993-1995 (Box 8, Folder 173)
  - Centennial Fund, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 174)
  - Centennial Fund, 1994-1997 (Box 9, Folder 175-176)
  - Centennial: WSCF history project - organization, 1992-1995 (Box 9, Folder 177-180)
  - Centennial: WSCF history project - women's history, 1993-1995 (Box 9, Folder 181)
  - Centennial: WSCF history project - member responses, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 182)
  - Centennial: WSCF history project - papers and reflections, 1993-1995 (Box 9, Folder 183)
  - Centennial: WSCF history project - papers and reflections, 1993-1995 (Box 10, Folder 184-187)
  - WSCF finances (Box 10, Folder 189-191)